Now if you want to take a pension policy, if you
want to take NT, then the
best joint life policy in the industry is that both husband and wife should
purchase it in a single policy and
both will get pension for life time, as long as the
husband is alive then the husband will get pension, when
he dies then the wife will get pension or
if whichever of the two lives till the end then the
pension will keep coming and when death occurs then the
family will get the paid premium, so this
type of plan is
NT plan, in which you
want to take immediate pension by paying a single premium, after
paying a single premium you can take a little referral pension, if you
want to take pension after 1 year then you have to read its
video on my
YouTube, you have to do limited pay,
not single pay, you have to do limited pay and
after that you have to take pension because
not everyone has a big corpus to invest at once, they
want to do it in parts,
if they want to do it in 4 years or 10 years, then they
want to take pension, so let us
see in which company you will get the highest pension,
as I have taken an example here.
That you are paying a premium of Rs 10 lakh, you
will pay a premium for Rs 5 lakh for 5 years, the husband is
50 years old and the wife is 45 years old and
here I have
taken pension plans of top companies like LIC, SBI, ICICI, STFC, Tata, Bajaj and how they
work, I will
tell you as a sample, then let us come to NT, for
example,
you purchase a plan, suppose you purchase
ICICI's Pension Flagship policy, in
which the husband is 50
years old and the wife is 45 years old and you
pay a premium of Rs 1 lakh for 5 years,
then you start taking pension after 10 years
and here you will see joint life with
return of premium, 100% of your money will also be
returned, so here you will see that you paid a
premium of Rs 10 lakh for 5 years,
after that you stopped for 5 years, then you get a
life time benefit of Rs 8728  Suppose income comes during this
period, if suppose the customer dies in the 10th year, then at that
time the death benefit of ₹ 70 lakh will be given
to the family members, the policy will be
closed but once the income starts,
after that you will keep getting a guaranteed income of ₹ 87000 from the policy,
now suppose if the husband
dies then the wife will keep getting income, if the
wife dies then the husband will keep getting income,
when both of them die then the
50 lakhs that you have paid will be returned,
if you want to surrender at any time
then you can also see the surrender benefit
in the column, you will also get the surrender benefit
in the policy,
so this is how this product will work, so we
see whose product is running at the top,
here I have taken company X
whose plan is Va, to know which company is this, you can contact
me on my mobile
number for consultation, comparison and purchase, there was a LIC Jeevan Dhara plan
which got closed in October.  After the new changes,
but there also the deferred
option was available which has been discontinued now.
SBI has Smart NT Plus but
even there this option in which
you get pension after paying premium every year is
not available. ICICI has a guaranteed pension
plan called Flex, where
you will get an
income of Rs 9792. If you pay premium every year, you
will stop for every year, that is, the
income will start from the sixth year when you turn 56.
HDFC has a Smart Pension
Plan available, in which if you pay premium for 5 years
and you take pension from the age of 56, then it will be Rs
4249. In AE, you will get an
income of Rs 8950 and in Bajaj, you will get an
income of Rs 3400. If you compare here, you are
getting Rs 33000 in this company. In one,
you are getting a pension of around Rs 380000. So,
you will see the difference of around Rs 76000 every year in life time extra benefit when you
compare and buy the policy in this manner
and whenever  If it happens then the 50 lakh rupees that you have paid will definitely be
refunded. Now, in the family, you are
taking another option in which you are
paying only 10 lakh rupees premium, you are paying premium for 5 years only,
but after paying premium for 5 years, you
also wait for 5 years, that is, you
start taking pension as per 61, then
in Company X's plan you will get an income of ₹22750,
in ICICI you will get ₹487000,
in HDFC's plan you will get ₹466317, in Tata you will get ₹474
and in Bajaj's pension plan
you will get ₹410000, so if you see the comparison in this way, there
is a difference of ₹000 for lifetime, so it will be
better for you to buy the policy after comparing, so if we talk about the age of now,
December
2024 is about to be completed in 2025 and at
this time if you want to purchase a pension policy for yourself, then
you can purchase it,
in the pension policy you can buy it at the age of 60-65  Even if you are 70 years
old, you can still purchase if you wish to do so.
Once you have
purchased the policy, its interest rate gets
locked forever and will never go down. So,
contact us as soon as possible to purchase. Thank you so much.